Krishna N Rastogi

Mobile: +91 8954925422 E-mail: krishrastogi3@gmail.com

Research Interests

My research interests span a wide range of topics in Cloud Computing, Big Data Analytics, Large Scale Infrastructure for Efficient Cloud Operations and Green Computing. In particular, I have been working on "Energy Efficient Algorithmic for Cloud Data Center Operations" and "High Performance Big Data Analytics in Cloud".

Education

2013-Present Ph.D. (Pursuing), Uttarakhand Technical University, Uttarakhand, India.

Advisor: Dr Priti Dimri, Associate Professor, GBPEC, Uttarakhand

Thesis Topic: Energy Efficient Algorithmics for Cloud Data Center Operations.

2007–2010 M.C.A, Babasaheb Bhimrao Ambedkar University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

2004–2007 B.Sc. in Information Technology, M C University, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh

Employment

Jan 2019- Present Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Applications, Faculty of Science, The Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, Vadodara, Gujrat Courses Taught: Cloud Computing, Internet of Things, Programming in Python, Discrete Mathematics, Cyber Security, Linear Algebra and Calculus, Data Communication and Networks, Digital Marketing Lab, Social Media Analytics

Aug 2014–Jan 2019 Assistant Professor, School of Technology, Doon University, Dehradun, Uttarakhand

Courses Taught: Operating Systems, Database Management Systems, Computer Organization and Architecture, Programming in C, Object Oriented Programming in C++, Cloud Computing, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Programming in Python, Data Structures using C. Secure Programming, Object Oriented Programming with Java, Internet of Things, Cryptography and Network Security.

Aug 2013—**Aug 2014** Teaching Assistant, Department of Computer Applications, G B Pant Engineering College, Pauri, Uttarakhand

Courses Assisted: *Operating Systems Concepts, Cryptography and Network Security.*

Skill Sets

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, Java

Databases: Oracle, PL/SQL, MySQL

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Angular

Tools: Hadoop, Spark, Tableau, R, Jupyter

Awards and Honors

•Qualified UGC NET for Assistant Professor in Computer Science and Applications in 2013

•TEQIP-II Fellowship to pursue Doctoral Studies in Computer Science from Uttarakhand Government.

Membership of Professional Bodies

•Member of CSI (Computer Society of India) since 2018.

Publications

Journal Papers

- •Krishna Nand Rastogi, Priti Dimri, Jitender Sehgal. "e-GiMod: Modeling an Information Highway for Cost Effective and Efficient e-Governance in India using Open Source Cloud Computing Services", International Journal of Advance Research in Computer Science and Software Engineering, Jan 2014
- •Krishna Kumar Singh, Priti Dimri and Krishna Nand Rastogi. "Implications of Big Data in Indian Stock Market", International Journal of Computer Applications, August 2014

Professional Engagement

Short Term Courses/FDP/Workshops Attended

- •One Week Short Term Course on Digital Signal & Image Processing at Jaypee University of Engineering and Technology, Guna form July 5th to 10th 2010.
- •One Week Short term Course on Eco-Technology for Sustainable Development at G B Pant Engineering College, Pauri form Oct 21th to 25th 2013
- •Five Days National Workshop on Challenges in Big Data Research at Malviya National Institute of Technology, Jaipur form Nov 9th to 13th 2013
- •One Week Short term Course on Advancements in Cloud Computing at G B Pant Engineering College, Pauri from May 27th to 31st 2014
- •One Week Short term Course on HADOOP and Its Applications at G B Pant Engineering College,

Pauri from Apr 21st to 25th 2015

•One day Workshop organized by NKN-Uttarakhand on June 10th, 2016.

Short Term Courses/FDP/Workshops Organized

- •Co-organized Two Week National FDP in Techno-Entrepreneurship in collaboration with Entrepreneurship Development Institute, (EDI), Gujrat at Doon University from 20/03/2015 to 31/03/2015
- •Organized a One Day Event on Digital India Initiative at Doon University on 06/07/2015.

MOOCs/Online Courses

- •Certificate of Completion of Power Searching with Google in July 2012
- •Certificate of Achievement in Big Data Analytics-Demos from Big Data University in July 2015
- •Certificate of Achievement in Big Data Fundamentals from Big Data University in July 2015
- •Certificate of Achievement in Introduction to Data Analysis using R from Big Data University in July 2015
- •Certificate of Achievement in Data Science Methodology from Big Data University in July 2015
- •Certificate of Achievement in Introduction to NoSQL and DBaaS from Big Data University in July 2015
- •Certificate of Completion in Introduction to R from DataCamp in July 2015
- •Honor Code Certificate in CS001x: MyCS: Computer Science for Beginners from edX in July 2015
- •Honor Code Certificate in CloudIntro.x: Introduction to Cloud Computing from edX –IEEE in July 2015
- •Certificate of Completion "Introduction to Python for Data Science" by DataCamp
- •Certificate of Achievement "Introduction to NoSQL and DBaaS" by Big Data University
- •Certificate of Completion "Microsoft SQL Server- An Introduction" by Udemy
- •Certificate of Completion "A Flying Introduction to Amazon Web Services: Cloud" by Udemy
- •Certificate of Completion "HANDS-ON SQL for Beginners (SELECT, FROM, WHERE)" from Udemv
- •Certificate of Completion "Oracle SQL Developer: Tips and Tricks" from Udemy
- •Certificate of Completion "Introduction to Learn T-SQL from Scratch" from Udemy
- •Certificate of Completion "Sachin Quickly Learns (SQL)- Structured Query Language" from Udemv
- •Certificate of Completion "Develop Database Application Without Manual Coding-Tremplin" from Udemy